JUAN FERREIRA

London, United Kingdom

Email: juanandres15@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Mobile: +44 7469770250

A versatile professional with over a decade of experience across finance, corporate management, and IT engineering. Leveraging seven years in finance roles within the corporate sector, coupled with three years in operational management within the food industry. Successfully transitioned to IT engineering, completing a Full Stack Developer diploma and currently pursuing further education in Data Engineering. Seeking an opportunity to merge financial acumen with evolving tech skills.

EXPERIENCE

IT Engineer 2023 - Current

Simultech IT LTD / Restore - London

- IT Services for medium and large businesses.
- Decommissioning and Recommissioning of office IT Equipment (Hardware, peripherals).
- Disposal of Computer/Office Equipment and Data Servers.
- Dismantling and Reinstalling Server Racks.

Full Stack Developer 2022-2023

OpenClassRoom - London

- Collaborated in agile teams to develop full-stack applications, employing TDD and user-focused design methodologies.
- Contributed to weekly exercises with diverse teams of up to six people, fostering a deep understanding of the development life cycle.
- Utilised agile methodology and software development techniques to overcome complex problems by implementing scrum and sprint processes.

Full Stack Developer 2022-2023

Top8 – 'The best sellers products for any category' - London

- Collaborated with a team of six to enhance communication through the development of a Progressive Web App (PWA) within four weeks.
- Contributed to the website's expansion by designing and implementing new sections, ensuring a thoughtful UI/UX design and a user-focused experience.
- Received commendation from employers for delivering a polished MVP and achieving a 98% job performance rating.

JUAN FERREIRA

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Shift Supervisor 2015-2020

Leon Restaurants, Compass Group, EasyCoffee - London

- Transformed and streamlined supply chain, logistics and operations across the regional central London locations, resulting in increased efficiency and sustainability. Successfully led and collaborated with a cross-functional team of 16 members, exceeding Head Office objectives.
- Pioneered a digital roster system for productivity updates, improving scheduling accuracy and providing real-time communication.
- Optimised inventory management with a 98% success rate through efficient tracking and management systems.

Consultant II, Consultant I, Administrative Assistant

2010-2015

KPMG Venezuela - Caracas

- Led consulting projects for diverse clients, specializing in internal audit, project management, and financial analysis within a dynamic cross-functional team.
- Managed administrative tasks for Petróleos de Venezuela, S.A. (PDVSA), overseeing financial analysis and audit-related expenses.
- Delivered Risk Compliance internal audit reports made every year. Made sure the firm complies with international standards by doing the appropriate tests and methods and preparing the documentation to be presented.

SKILLS & TOOLS

HTML - CSS – SASS – Libraries	React – Nextjs	Agile	Budgeting
Javascript – Typescript	Express	Figma – UI Design	Communication
JEST	PostgreSQL – MongoDB	Git - Github	Data Analysis
Office 365 (Full Package)	Firebase	SAP	Teamwork

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developer (Diploma)

2022 - 2023

OpenClassRoom - Remote

AAT Professional Diploma in Accounting (Level 3)

2018 - 2020

Bromley College of Further & Higher Education - London